SALAMI ABIODUN

Gbagada Lagos | +2348154224416 | Salamabiodun01@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Talented Technical Support Representative with gift for understanding needs of both business and home users. Versed in troubleshooting and desktop support on Windows, Linux and Mac systems. Proven skill in resolving problems quickly on first call. Information Security Specialist with passion for aligning security architecture plans and processes with security standards and business goals. Extensive experience developing and testing security framework for cloud-based software. Versed in robust network defense strategies.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Security Protocols
- LAN Protocols
- Hardware Installations
- Company Policy Adherence
- Software updates
- Confidential data management
- End-user support
- Microsoft Hyper-V Server
- Data security

- Qualys Cloud Platform
- Nagios monitoring software
- Developing security plans
- Symantec Endpoint Protection
- Implementing security programs
- Wireshark software
- Erecting firewalls
- Critical thinking skills
- Organization and Time Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALADDIN DIGITAL BANK

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST

2021-Present

- Developed and maintained strong client relationships to deliver exceptional customer service and problem resolution.
- Set up network profiles, security permissions and file sharing systems.
- Worked closely with management teams to plan, develop and execute technical strategies aligned to client's vision
- Controlled and managed server room, wireless network, server infrastructure, audiovisual equipment, laptops and video conferencing equipment.
- Facilitated best user experience through continuous support and communication of system changes.
- Resolved escalated issues by serving as subject matter expert on wide-ranging issues.
- Performed daily system monitoring, verifying integrity and availability of hardware, server resources, systems and key processes.
- Liaised effectively with others to promote ongoing network design, reevaluation and optimization, scaling with company growth.
- Assisted with updating technical support best practices for use by team.

CEASARS LUXURY HOTEL

INFORMATION SECURITY ANALYST

2019-2021

- Monitored computer virus reports to determine when to update virus protection systems.
- Conducted security audits to identify vulnerabilities.
- Monitored use of data files and regulated access to protect secure information.
- Worked with other teams to enforce security of applications and systems.
- Investigated and resolved incidents of unauthorized access to sensitive information.
- Developed, tested and implemented security policies, plans and procedures for organizational protection.
- Executed penetration testing to identify security weaknesses and develop disaster recovery plans.
- Administered and monitored firewalls, intrusion detection systems and anti-virus software to detect risks.
- Educated and trained users on information security policies and procedures.

EDUCATION

Polytechnic Ibadan (HND) Electrical Electronics 2013-2017

PROFESSIONAL TOOLS

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP | ADOBE PREMIER PRO | CANVA | FIGMA | HTML5 | CSS 3

REFERENCE

Available on request